

# Yvette Ali, CAPM®

PROJECTS | OPERATIONS | PROGRAMS

# 954.760.1003







### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF ARTS
Major: Organizational Mgt.
Minor: Project Mgt.
Ashford University

# **EXPERTISE**

**Board Relations** 

Community Outreach

Data Management

Grant/Project Management

**Human Resources** 

Operations

Partnership Building

**Process Engineering** 

Program Development

**Quality Control** 

Social Media Marketing

Strategic Planning

Résumé Writing

## **PROFILE**

Over 14 years' progressive experience in program development, project management, operational streamlining, and partnership-building in private, government, and non-profit industries. Accomplished in planning and executing projects from concept to execution, while deeply committed to delivering quality outcomes. A thoughtful and progressive thinker with successful experience in demanding work environments requiring high levels of preciseness.

Practiced in using business analysis practices to identify opportunities/challenges. Talented at setting the gold standard in the development of templates, practices, and frameworks in process improvement. Strong aptitude for emerging technologies with eminent communication skills. A born mentor, with an unsurpassed work ethic and contagious enthusiasm geared towards building positive relationships. Strong multicultural sensitivity and literacy. Intellectually curious, able to self-start solution discovery (exhibit owner mentality). Bilingual: English and Spanish.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE PROJECT MANAGER, <u>Lumen Technologies</u> | June 2023 – April 2024 Served as project manager for low-risk, low-complexity telecom development projects assigned by PMO office. This entailed end-to-end PM domains including SOW analysis, kick-off presentations, building project plans, governance, and escalations. Heavy coordination with contracted vendors and internal sales teams in scheduling install/turn-up of Lumen network services and CPE orders to achieve customer- desired dates. Key contributions:

- Established relationships, confidence, and security with vendors and customers through sensitivity, quick response, and attention to detail.
- Took the lead in the development of an APM Playbook and creation of project lifecycle workflow, allowing the unit to take advantage of better resources for continued growth.

**DIRECTOR**, The Children's Museum of St. Croix | Remote (2022 – 2023) Worked closely with the Board of Directors in meeting this non-profit's fundraising, capacity-building, and systems-creation goals. Entailed guiding event planning, process improvement, strategy, and technical guidance on marketing, database creation, and project planning. **Key accomplishments**:

- Built a comprehensive donor database of over 700 constituents which reduced time spent managing data, creating a disciplined approach to data management.
- Designed and implemented forms, reports, images, marketing material, and usable business templates for non-profits and fundraising events.
- With a 6-week timeline, worked with the Board to plan and execute a successful fundraiser/auction event to ensure a full house and meet the fundraising target. Used Qtego platform for event registrations/management.
- Created social media marketing campaigns with insightful information to promote and create community awareness of the museum. Increased Facebook page traffic by 50% and tripled followers in 3 months.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### Remote collaboration tools:

Zoom, Skype, Google Hangouts, GoToMeeting, Sharepoint, Slack, MS Teams, Dropbox, Canva

Document Software: MS Office 365 (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Copilot), Google Workspace.

Additional: ADP, Asana,
Basecamp, Bloomerang, Canva,
Celoxsis, Concur, MS Project,
PowerBl, Trello, Quickbase,
CRMS, HRMs, Social Media
(Facebook/ Instagram/Twitter/
TikTok/ Snapchat)

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Adaptive Management

Communication

Creativity

Critical thinking

Decision-making

Driven

Emotional Intelligence

Integrity

Leadership

Motivator

Organization

Problem-solving

Resourcefulness

Situational Awareness

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Associate in Project
Management (CAPM®)
Certified Résumé Writer
Lean Culture Certified (LCC)™
Six Sigma Black Belt Professional

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE continued

PROJECT DIRECTOR, EQUUS Workforce Solutions | St. Croix (2021 - 22)
Reporting to the Regional Manager, led a staff of 10 under a 1.3M contract with over 70 project deliverables and program objectives aligned with the Workforce Investment Opportunity Act (WIOA). Recognized twice for company's LEGACY company values: servant leadership and initiative. Key accomplishments:

- Within 90 days of contract, led the seamless transition of both One Stop Career
   Centers ensuring critical partnership collaboration.
- Created functional operational practices in communications, SOPs, workflows, process optimization, and reporting aligned with the needs of internal & external partners.
- Maintained fiscal accountability and budget forecast at 95% accuracy.
- Recruited and onboarded staffing for both American Job Centers within 30 days.
- Successfully monitored/maintained progress toward attainment of contract's Negotiated Performance Goals (NPG).

### PROJECT ANALYST, The Strategy Group | St. Croix (2020 - 21)

Supported assigned disaster recovery projects by coordinating data and deliverables to help push projects from start to finish. Drove the prioritization of project tasks/timelines to bring projects to conclusion and on time with a focus on providing detailed, accurate, and timely updates and capturing risks/issues. Coordinated information-gathering sessions and reviews with users to clearly define needs and work plans. **Key accomplishments**:

- Provided support in complex disaster recovery and CDBG projects from concept to fully developed schedules and risk registers for the UVI Multipurpose Complex/Emergency Shelter Project and the JFL Temporary Hardened Structure projects.
- Fostered and maintained strong business partner and client relationships through consistent, proactive, and thorough communications by providing guidance and technical support for UVI and JFL projects.
- Automated processes for assigned projects and implemented improvement initiatives in meeting facilitation which enhanced overall efficiency.

VAL CREW LEAD, U.S. Department of Homeland Security, FEMA | St. Croix (2019 - 20) As a federal point of contact for non-profit agencies post Hurricane Maria, served as one of the central coordination points between local, territorial, Federal government and voluntary/faith-based/ community organizations. Key contributions:

- Under the Recovery Support Function (RSF), worked closely with territorial Long-Term Recovery Groups (LTRGs) and State Voluntary Organizations Active in Disaster (VOAD) in community and volunteer outreach.
- Delivered technical guidance and built relationships among local government and voluntary, faith-based, and community-based organizations.
- Analyzed impact of unmet needs for program planning and advocacy.

# **EARLY CAREER**

#### **DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS**

Serene Business Centers, United Arab Emirates | 2017 - 2019

### ONLINE BUSINESS MANAGER / RÉSUMÉ WRITER

Self-Employed Freelancer, USA and UAE | 2013 - 2017

#### **PROGRAM MANAGER**

Working Excellence Capital Partners, St. Croix | 2012 - 2013

#### SUBSTANCE ABUSE PROGRAM ADMINISTRATOR

Pinnacle Services, L.L.C. St. Croix, | 2011 - 2012